Privacy and cookie notice
=========================

Introduction
------------

### Who are we?

We are NTS Live Ltd, a company incorporated and registered in England and Wales with registered address at 89a Kingsland High Street, London E8 2PB, United Kingdom with registered ("**NTS**", "**we**" or "**us**").  
  
Where we decide the means or purpose of processing your personal data, we are the "data controller."

### What’s this notice about?

This notice explains how we process your personal data as a data controller in relation to your use of NTS’s mobile application and website application, which both provide access to NTS’s global radio platform (the "**Platform**").  
  
We update this notice from time to time, so please check back in on a regular basis.  
  
Please note that other websites or services mentioned on the Platform are not operated by us, and you should refer to the privacy policies on those websites to understand how your personal data is being used.

### What are your rights?

You have the following rights, although these rights may be limited in some circumstances:

* Ask us to send a copy of your personal data to you or someone else
* Ask us to restrict, stop processing, or delete your personal data
* Object to our processing of your personal data
* Object to use of your personal data for direct marketing purposes
* Ask us to correct inaccuracies in your personal data

If we rely on consent to process data, or send direct marketing, you can withdraw consent by email to the address below.

### How do you contact us?

If you have any questions concerning this notice, including how you can exercise your rights, please contact us at: [dpo@ntslive.co.uk](mailto:dpo@ntslive.co.uk)  
  
If we can’t resolve your issue, you can also get in touch with the Information Commissioner’s Office: [https://ico.org.uk/concerns](https://ico.org.uk/concerns)  
(or if you live in a European country other than the UK, you can submit a complaint to the supervisory authority in your country).

Your personal data and how we use it
------------------------------------

### Account Registration Data

We process the following information to register your account on the Platform (the "**My NTS Account**"):

* Email address
* Password

#### How we use it

We process this information as it is necessary for the performance of a contract, being the NTS Terms of Use.

#### Sources

We collect this data from you.

#### Recipients

We share this information with:

* Google Firebase, and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy).
* Rocket Science Group LLC ("Mailchimp"), and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

### NTS Shop Data

We process the following information to fulfil any orders you make via the Platform:

* Name of recipient
* Email address
* Payment details
* Order details
* Shipping details (including recipient address)
* Billing address

#### How we use it

We process this information as it is necessary for the performance of a contract, being the sale contract between you and NTS, in relation to orders made via the Platform's shop ("**NTS Shop**").

#### Sources

We collect this data from you.

#### Recipients

The NTS Shop is run by Universal Music Operations Limited. You can access their privacy policy [here](https://www.umusic.co.uk/privacy.html).  
  
We use PayPal (Europe) S.a.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A. to handle payments for subscriptions to the Platform ("**NTS Supporters**"). You can access their privacy policy [here](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).  
  
We use Shopify International Limited for log-in authentication purposes. You can access their privacy policy [here](https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy).  
  
We use Apple Pay and Google Pay to process certain transactions made via the NTS Shop. You can access Google Pay’s privacy policy [here](https://payments.google.com/payments/apis-secure/get_legal_document?ldo=0&ldt=privacynotice&ldl=en-GB) and Apple Pay’s privacy policy [here](https://www.apple.com/uk/legal/privacy/data/en/apple-pay/).

### Marketing Data

We process the following information to make suggestions and recommendations to you about: (i) news and updates relating to us, our partners, products, services and content; (ii) content, goods and services that may interest you; and (iii) other promotional activity and events we think may be of interest:

* Email address
* Other information collected and clearly identifiable to you at the point of your signing up to our marketing communications

#### How we use it

If required by law, we process this information by relying upon your consent in order for us to undertake this data processing activity. You can revoke your consent at any time by letting us know, including by emailing us.  
  
In some instances (such as with some of our existing customers) the law may permit us to process your personal data in order to send marketing communications on the basis of our legitimate interests, being our legitimate business interests in marketing our activities and promoting the success of our business and our websites, content, products and services. If the information is not of interest for you, you can opt-out at any time by letting us know, including by emailing us.

#### Sources

We collect this data from you.

#### Recipients

We share this information with: Google Firebase, and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy). Rocket Science Group LLC ("Mailchimp"), and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

### Technical Data

We process the following information about the device, on which you are accessing the Platform, in order to tailor our delivery of the Platform, including:

* Browser type and settings, IP address, approximate location, access logs, device type and settings, operating system, and other information provided by your browser
* The use you make of our Platform, including which pages you visit, which links you click on, the websites you have come from, how long you spend on our Platform and how you interact with it
* Details of which adverts you have seen (for example, to avoid showing you them again)

#### How we use it

We process this information on the basis of our legitimate interests, being to improve the delivery of our Services (including by understanding how you use the Services).

This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Terms of Service](https://policies.google.com/terms) apply.

#### Sources

In addition to the sources listed in Section 3 (Cookies, analytics and similar technologies), we collect this information via apilayer Data Products GmbH ("ipstack"), and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://www.ideracorp.com/Legal/APILayer/PrivacyStatement).

#### Recipients

We share this information with:

* Google Firebase, and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy).
* Rocket Science Group LLC ("Mailchimp"), and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).
* Amazon Web Services, and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/).

### Submissions, Enquiries and Requests Data

We may process the following information so that we are able to collect, record and properly respond to your submissions, enquiries and support requests in relation to the Platform:

* Name
* Contact details (including email address and telephone number)
* Any other information that you submit as part of your enquiry or request (such as a description of the issue you are experiencing or audio data submitted to NTS).

#### How we use it

We process this information on the basis of our legitimate interests, being to: (i) ensure that the Platform functions properly so that our users have the best experience when using the Platform; (ii) improve the quality of the Platform, and provide a better experience to our users; (iii) identify and correct any bugs in the Platform; and (iv) provide certain functionalities on the Platform.

#### Sources

We collect this data from you.

#### Recipients

We share this information with:

* Freshdesk Inc., and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://www.freshworks.com/privacy/?_ga=2.107728770.1021340995.1635789557-934834880.1635789557).
* Formspree, Inc. when you submit field recordings, and you can access their privacy policy [here](https://formspree.io/legal/privacy-policy).

Cookies, analytics and similar technologies
-------------------------------------------

Cookies, pixels and other technologies store and access data on your device to help websites and apps work. This table explains their purpose, how long they last, and who else can access their data. We get your consent to use them unless they’re essential for our sites, apps or services.  
  
Most browsers allow control over cookies, for more information: [Google Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en) | [Microsoft Edge](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy) | [Mozilla Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences) | [Microsoft Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies) | [Opera](https://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/privacy/) | [Apple Safari](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/safari).

### Live Tracks Notification

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To record if a user wants to receive browser notifications when a new song starts on one of our live audio streams

**Access**: We use ACRCloud LIMITED to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how ACRCloud LIMITED uses data by clicking [here](https://www.acrcloud.com/privacy/).

### Shopify Multipass Authentication

**Duration**: 24h

**Purpose**: To enable users to log-in to the NTS Shop using the NTS Account.

**Access**: We use Shopify to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how Shopify uses data by clicking [here](https://www.shopify.com/legal/privacy).

### Last Visit

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To record when users last visited the Platform.

**Access**: N/A

### Promo Modal Dismissed

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To ensure that users receive appropriate and relevant promotional content.

**Access**: We use Google Firebase to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how Google Firebase uses data by clicking [here](https://firebase.google.com/support/privacy).

### Audio Volume

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To record users’ audio settings preferences.

**Access**: N/A

### PayPal Storage

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To store account details in order to ensure secure transactions made via PayPal.

**Access**: We use PayPal to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how PayPal uses data by clicking [here](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

### Google Analytics

**Duration**: Two years

**Purpose**: To collect information about how people interact with our Platform and generate reports based to identify problems, understand how people use our Platform, and improve them.

**Access**: We use Google Analytics to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how Google uses personal data by clicking [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).  
You can opt-out here: [Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).  

### Meta Pixel

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To match your visit on our website to your Facebook User account. Once matched, we and our partners can optimise our ad campaigns.

**Access**: We use Meta Pixel to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how Meta uses personal data by clicking [here](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policies/cookies).  
You can opt-out here: [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=privacy) | [Instagram](https://www.instagram.com/accounts/privacy_and_security/).  

### TikTok Pixel

**Duration**: Indefinite

**Purpose**: To match your visit on our website to your TikTok user account. Once matched, we and our partners can optimise our ad campaigns.

**Access**: We use TikTok Pixel to set these cookies.  
You can find out more about how TikTok uses personal data by clicking [here](https://www.tiktok.com/legal/page/global/cookie-policy/en).  

### Hotjar

**Duration**: One year

**Purpose**: To collect information about user journeys to understand how people use our Platform, and improve them.

**Access**: We use Hotjar to set these cookies. More info [here](https://help.hotjar.com/hc/en-us/articles/6952777582999-Cookies-Set-by-the-Hotjar-Tracking-Code).  

Storage, transfers and disclosure
---------------------------------

### Data retention

We hold personal data for as long as necessary bearing in mind the purpose for which it was collected. At the end of the retention period, we assess whether it is necessary to continue to retain information to achieve the purposes for which it was collected. To determine appropriate retention periods, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of unauthorised access, and legal requirements.

### Storage & Transfers

Where we use data processors outside the UK and European Economic Area, and transfer personal data to a country which does not provide an adequate level of protection, we use contracts which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe and the UK. For more information drop us a line using the contact details at the start of this notice.

### Disclosure

Other than as set out above, we may disclose your personal data:

* Where required by law, government, competent authorities or the courts or to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights, and for the purposes of preventing crime and fraud (for example, we may share personal data with our professional advisors, investigators, or credit reference agencies).
* With suppliers and subcontractors, as necessary for the purposes set out in this notice.
* If involved in an investment, merger, acquisition, or sale of our organisation or assets, personal data we hold may be shared on the basis of the legitimate interests of us, our shareholders, customers and other parties to a transaction, unless those interests are outweighed by prejudicial impacts upon you.

This privacy notice is published on November 2021.

Up Next

0:00:00

0:00:00

### Up Next

Similar to what you are listening to

Sorry, we couldn't find any episodes.  
Please try again later...

Play

Live now

1

Play

2

Play

1

[Next on 1](https://www.nts.live/schedule) …

2

[Next on 2](https://www.nts.live/schedule/2) …

Personalised Recommendations
----------------------------

Sign up or log in to MY NTS and get personalised recommendations

Unlock Live Tracklists
----------------------

Support NTS for timestamps across live channels and the archive

Find out more

### Live on 1

No tracks found...
